Lilian Hunout

+33781984502 @ lilian.hunout@outlook.com in lilian-hunout

Profile

I am passionate about data science, machine learning with over two years of experience specializing in Python development and algorithms.

I adapt quickly and I have an ease to collaborate. Motivated and persevering, I like to work on different projects to develop my skills

Mainly looking for Machine Learning/Data Scientist positions. I am ready to meet the future challenges that will come my way.

Links_

GitHub **lhunout**

% Website lhunout.github.io

Skills_

Programming

Python • R • C • MATLAB (Simulink) • SQL

Libraries

Keras • Tensorflow • PyTorch • Pandas • NumPy • Scikit-learn • Matplolib • ggplot2

Miscellaneous

Shell • Windows • Linux • Linux Tools • CUDA • Docker • Slurm • ETEX• Markdown • Microsoft Office • Jupyter • Git • Jira (Agile/Scrum)

Embedded systems

ARM • ATmega

Soft Skills

teamwork • time management • problem-solving • documentation • communication • presentation skills • report writing

Languages

English (professionnal proficiency, TOEIC 845/990) • French (native proficiency, voltaire certificate - business)

Competition.

STARTUPWEEKEND

Mov. 2019

♀ Bourges, FR

- 54-hour entrepreneurship educational competitive event
- "My farmer's basket": connecting local producers with customers

Interests_

- Sports: mountain biking, judo, snowboarding
- Trips abroad

Experience

Eviden, Atos

AI & COMPUTER VISION RESEARCH INTERN

Feb. 2023 - Aug. 2023

- **♀** Grenoble, FR
- Big Data & Security division, European project PREVENT PCP
- Detection of abandoned luggage in video streams to improve station safety and limit false alerts to abandoned baggage.
- Implementation of score-based object/owner association algorithms.

MBDA, Airbus

EMBEDDED AI INTERN

🛗 Apr. 2022 - Sep. 2022

♀ Bourges, FR

 Implementation of communication protocols, creation of an embedded Linux image on a Xilinx Zynq card, setting up a Vitis AI Docker environment, development of an image classification model.

Education

INSA Centre Val de Loire

MENG IN INDUSTRIAL SYSTEMS

Sep. 2018 - Current

♀ Bourges, FR

- GPA: 4.0
- Courses: statistical theory and methods, machine learning, computer vision, complex systems engineering, risk management
- Student representative, active participation in various events (student council campaign, open days, etc.)

University of Tours

MRES IN ELECTRONICS, ELECTRICAL ENERGY & AUTOMATIC CONTROL (E3A)

Sep. 2022 - Current

♀ Tours, FR

• Courses: cyber-physical system, multiphysics modelling

TalTech

School of Information Technologies (Erasmus+ exchange)

🛗 Sep. 2021 - Jan. 2022

♀ Tallinn, EE

- GPA: 3.7
- **Courses:** data mining, machine learning, system programming, embedded systems

University Projects

PRISME Laboratory

TRACKING AND DETECTION OF MICROROBOTS

🛗 Feb. 2022 - Apr. 2022

♀ Bourges, FR

• Research project with a doctoral student in a robotics and vision research laboratory.

TalTech Embedded AI Research Lab

GARAGE DOOR CYCLE DETECTION MODEL

Mov. 2021 - Jan. 2022

♀ Tallinn, EE

- End of semester project of the Machine Learning for Embedded Systems course.
- First prize 250€